Finding Aid for the Collection of Big Band Photographs PASC-M.0088
UCLA Library Special Collections
Collection of Big Band photographs
1930-1945
UCLA Library Special Collections
PASC-M.0088
0.5 Linear Feet (1 box)
The collection consists of commercial publicity photographs of American dance bands, combo bands and singers.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Custodial History
This collection was acquired by the UCLA Music Library. When the Music Library special collections was merged under the umbrella of UCLA Library Special Collections, this collection was transferred to LSC.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9910202303606533
Scope and Content
Collection mostly consists of commercial publicity photographs of American dance bands, combo bands and singers, such as Ray Herback, Tiny Hill, Hoosier Hot Shots, Eddy Howard, Dick Jurgens, Gene Krupa, Jack Leonard, Light Crust Doughboys, Louise Massey and the Westerners, Frankie Masters, Ray Noble, Kate Smith, Alec Templeton, Orrin Tucker and Bonnie Baker, Horace Henderson, Eddy Duchin, Count Basie, Cab Calloway, Roy Acuff and his Smokey Mountain Boys, Gene Autry, Horace Heidt, Charlie Winninger, Benny Goodman's Sensational Swing Band, Paul Whiteman, and others.
Unless otherwise noted, all items are photographs.
- Acuff, Roy (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Scope and Contents note
  With his Smokey Mountain Boys
- Alexander, Van (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Ash, Paul (Box 1, Folder 109)
  With members of the "Paul Ash Every Week Club."
- Autry, Gene (Box 1, Folder 21)
  General note
  With list of releases
- Ayres, Mitchell (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Barnet, Charlie (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Basie, Count (Box 1, Folder 18)
  2 copies with list of releases
- Biamonte, Louis (Box 1, Folder 72)
  With: Frank chase; Andre Kostelanetz; Toots Mondello and Chester Hazlett.
- Boswell, Connie (Box 1, Folder 80)
- Bradley, Will (Box 1, Folder 54)
  With Bill Corti and Jimmy Emery.
- Bradley, Will (Box 115)
- Bruce, Carol (Box 1, Folder 81)
- Byrne, Bobby (Box 1, Folder 77)
- Calloway, Cab (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Cavallaro, Carmen (Box 1, Folder 106)
- Cavallaro, Carmen (Box 1, Folder 119)
- Chester, Bob (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Davis, Johnnie (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Dillagene (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Donahue, Al (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Donohue, Al (Box 1, Folder 114)
- Dorsey, Jimmy (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Dorsey, Tommy (Box 1, Folder 73)
- Dorsey, Tommy (Box 1, Folder 74)
- Duchin, Eddy (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Duren, Joe (Box 1, Folder 53)
  With Tommy Tucker and Kerwin Sommerville.
- Edwards, Joan (Box 1, Folder 79)
- Elman, Ziggy (Box 1, Folder 93)
- Ennis, Skinnay (Box 1, Folder 92)
- Ferrin, Harald (Box 1, Folder 118)
- Fields, Shep (Box 1, Folder 75)
- Fields, Shep (Box 1, Folder 76)
  Inscribed
- Scott Fisher's Orchestra (Box 1, Folder 99)
- Goodman, Benny (Box 1, Folder 50)
  Swing band.
- Goodman, Benny (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Goodman, Benny (Box 1, Folder 113)
- Gordon, Gray (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Gordon, Gray (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Glen Gray's Brass Section, 1935 April 10 (Box 1, Folder 103)
  Includes: Billy Rauch; Sonny Durham; Grady Watts; Pee Wee Hunt; Bobby Jones and Fritz Hummel.
- Glen Gray's Reed Section (Box 1, Folder 101)
  Includes: Pat Davis; Art Ralson; clarence Hutchenrider; Kenny Sargent and Glen Gray.
- Gray, Glen (Box 1, Folder 90)
- Green, Johnny (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Hall, George (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Heidt, Horace (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Heidt, Horace (Box 1, Folder 24)
  With Jimmy Skiles.
- Henderson, Horace (Box 1, Folder 16)
  2 copies
- Herback, Ray (Box 1, Folder 1)
  4 copies
- Woody Herman Saxes (Box 1, Folder 140)
- Herman, Woody (Box 1, Folder 105)
- Woody Herman Invitations (Box 1, Folder 110)
  Invitations to publicity appearances.
- Herth, Milt (Box 1, Folder 89)
- Hildegarde (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Hill, Tiny (Box 1, Folder 2)
  2 copies.
- Himber, Richard (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Hoosier Hot Shots (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Horlick, Harry (Box 1, Folder 83)
- Howard, Eddy (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Howard, Shirley (Box 1, Folder 48)
- James, Harry (Box 1, Folder 61)
- James, Harry (Box 1, Folder 62)
- James, Sonny (Box 1)
  In folders 126-128.
- Sonny James Orchestra (Box 1)
  In folders 129-136
- Sonny James Orchestra (Box 1, Folder 124)
  Incribed, "to the Rossmans from Sonny James and his orchestra."
- Sonny James Orchestra (Box 1, Folder 125)
- The Jesters (Box 1, Folder 85)
- Jurgens, Dick (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Kassel, Art (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Kaye, Sammy (Box 1, Folder 104)
- Kemp, Hal (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Kemp, Hal (Box 1, Folder 35)
- King, Wayne (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Koven, Jack, 1935 February 12 (Box 1, Folder 102)
  With: John D'Agostino and Jimmy Milazzo.
- Kress, Carl (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Krupa, Gene (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Lang, Eddie (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Leonard, Jack (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Paul Lev Orchestra (Box 1, Folder 141)
  Inscribed.
- Light Crust Doughboys (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Lombardo, Guy (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Long, Johnny (Box 1, Folder 86)
- Vincent Lopez Sax Section (Box 1, Folder 100)
  Includes: Edward Anderson; Larry Tise; Vincent Lopez; George Tudor and Stanley Worth.
- Vincent Lopez Sax Section (Box 1, Folder 100)
- Lucas, Nick (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Luther, Frank (Box 1, Folder 88)
- William Madden Orchestra (Box 1, Folder 122)
- William Madden Orchestra (Box 1, Folder 123)
- Manone, Wingy (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Martin, Freddy (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Martin, Tony (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Martin, Tony (Box 1, Folder 111)
  publicity postcard
- Masse, Louise (Box 1, Folder 9)
  With the Westerners
  3 copies with list of releases
- Masters, Frankie (Box 1, Folder 10)
- McCoy, Clyde (Box 1, Folder 82)
- McMichen, Clayton (Box 1, Folder 64)
  With his Georgia Wildcats.
- Bennie Meroff's Brass, 1934 November (Box 1, Folder 68)
  Includes: Red Pepper; Al King; Larry Powell; Jack Marshall and Ford Caufield.
- The Merry Mals (Box 1, Folder 91)
- Miller, Glenn (Box 36)
- Moore, Don (Box 1, Folder 60)
  With: Mickey Bloom; Harry Wilford; Red Stanley and Bill Robertson.
- Morgan, Russ (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Myers, D.E. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Myers, D.E., 1936 July 4 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Ozzie Nelson's Brass, 1935 January 4 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  Includes: Boe Ashford; Harry Johnson; Abe Lincoln; Elmer and Holly Humphreys.
- Nichols, Red (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Nichols, Red (Box 1, Folder 112)
- Noble, Ray (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Reynolds, Tommy (Box 1, Folder 12)
- The Rhythm Knights, 1936 November 12 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  Inscribed, "To my friends at Irvings, Clem Wasleski." Atlantic City, N.J.
- Rios, Elvira (Box 1, Folder 87)
- Robertson, Dick (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Saltzman, Ben, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 117)
  With: Tom Longley; John Harold Ferrin. Inscribed, "Best Wishes to Irving Music Shoppe. Ben Saltzman."
- Smith, Kate (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Dick Stabile Sax Section, 1936 September 4 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  Includes: Fred Pfeifer; Joe Stabile; Adrian Tei; George Kaetz and Dick Stabile.
- Dick Stabile Sax Section (Box 1, Folder 138)
- Stabile, Dick (Box 1, Folder 137)
- Teagarden, Jack (Box 1, Folder 69)
  With Charlie Teagarden.
- Templeton, Alex (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Todd, Dick (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Tucker, Orrin (Box 1, Folder 15)
  With Bonnie Baker.
- Tucker, Tommy (Box 1, Folder 116)
- Unidentified Saxophonist (Box 1, Folder 142)
- Unidentified Woman (Box 1, Folder 139)
- Rudy Vallee Orchestra Brass, 1934 December 26 (Box 1, Folder 108)
  Includes: Red Stanley; Don Moore; Mickey Bloom; Harry Wilford and Bill Robertson.
- Vallee, Rudy (Box 1, Folder 107)
  With Frank Staff.
- Weems, Ted (Box 1, Folder 84)
- Welk, Lawrence (Box 1, Folder 78)
- Whiteman, Paul (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Whiteman, Paul (Box 1, Folder 65)
  With: Helen Foster; Rita Walsh and Norman Paige.
- Whiteman, Paul (Box 1, Folder 121)
- Wiener, Jeanne (Box 1, Folder 45)
  At the console of the organ in the music stall of the Street Pier, Atlantic City, N.J.
- Wiener, Jeanne (Box 1, Folder 94)
- Wiener, Jeanne (Box 1, Folder 95)
  With her accordion
- Winniger, Charlie (Box 1, Folder 23)
  With Ralph Winger, Jerry "Muscle" Bowne and Jimmy Skiles.